Guide to the Thomas Davidson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS AND MEMORABILIA, Series IV
  - Calling cards, business cards, undated (Box 33)
  - Cartes de visite, photographs, undated (Box 33)
  - Bills, receipts, etc., 1861-1901, undated (Box 33)
  - Bankbook and checkbooks, 1887-1893 (Box 33)
  - Engraving plate, undated (Box 33)
  - Clippings (Box 33)
  - Miscellaneous printed matter (Box 33)
  - Annotated research material: reprints of others' articles, etc. (Box 34)
- EDWARD ENDELMAN MATERIAL, Series V
  - (Most of this material pertains to Davidson; it includes correspondence about him, and papers prepared for his classes, with an occasional note by him.)
  - Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous, 1900-1908 (Box 35)
    - William T. Harris, 1901-1904, 1915 (Box 35)
  - "Paper for Memorial at Glenmore" and "History of Class", 1901 (Box 35)
  - Papers for courses, 1901-1905, undated (Box 35)
  - "Hume's Fallacy and the Doctrine of Causation" (M.A. thesis, N.Y.U.), 1903 (Box 35)
- ADDITIONAL MATERIALS ON MICROFILM
  These films were collected and donated by John Roemischer. They were filmed between 1961 and 1964, at the following institutions: nos. 2-5, 7-10, and 12 at the New York Public Library; no. 1 at Harvard University Library; no. 6 at Yale University Library; no. 11 at the University of California at Berkley; no. 13 at the American Jewish Periodical Center in Cincinnati; and no. 15 at Queen's University of Belfast. There is no record of the filming of no. 14.
  The present film consists of the following 15 negative films, spliced together on two reels.
  - TD letters to
    - Henry Wadsworth Longfellow (film 1), 1867-1876 (Reel 36)
    - Charles Eliot Norton (film 1), 1867 (Reel 36)
    - James Russell Lowell (film 1), 1876 (Reel 36)
  - TD, "Lecture on Tennyson's 'In Memoriam" (film 1), 1891 (Reel 36)
  - TD letters to [C.S. Smith?] (film 2), 1898 (Reel 36)
  - TD typescript, "Greek Democracies" (film 2), [1898?] (Reel 36)
  - American Art Review: TD articles (film 3)
    - "Praxiteles' Hermes with the Infant Dionysos", 1880 (Reel 36)
    - "The Literature of the Tanagra Figurines", 1880 (Reel 36)
    - Review of F.F.G. von Ravensburg's Die Venus von Milo, 1880 (Reel 36)
    - "Private Collections of Ancient Sculpture in Rome", 1881 (Reel 36)
    - Review of Henry Schliemann's Ilios, 1881 (Reel 36)
    - "The New Frescos in the Benedictine Abbey at Monte Cassino", 1881 (Reel 36)
  - American Dante Society. Year Book (film 4)
    - List of officers, "Historical," Constitution, 1891 (Reel 36)
    - TD, "The Teachers of Dante", 1891 (Reel 36)
    - William T. Harris (WTH), "Dante's Doctrine of Sin", 1891 (Reel 36)
  - Current Literature: TD, "The Unity of Education" (film 5), 1897 (Reel 36)
  - Freethinkers' Magazine (film 6)
    - TD, "Co-Operation", 1887 (Reel 36)
    - Thaddeus Burr Wakeman (TBW), "How to Co-operate", 1887 (Reel 36)
    - TD, "A Freethought University," "Free-thought Education", 1887 (Reel 36)
    - TBW, "A Freethought College," and letters on the subject from William T. Eichholz and W.D. Leary, 1887 (Reel 36)
    - TBW, "Giordano Bruno in the Past, Present and Future", [1887?] (Reel 36)
    - TD, "The Source of Economic Law", 1889 (Reel 36)
    - "Prof. Bovio's Address at the Bruno Celebration," translated by TD, [1889?] (Reel 36)
    - TD, "Bruno's Thought", [1889?] (Reel 36)
    - Kleanthes the Stoic, "Hymn to Jove," translated by TD, [1889?] (Reel 36)
  - Boston: Index Association/ TD, "Giordano Bruno" (film 7), [1886?] (Reel 36)
  - Daniel G. Brinton and TD, "Giordano Bruno: Philosopher and Martyr" (film 8), 1890 (Reel 36)
  - Journal of Social Science (film 9)
    - WTH, "The Definition of Social Science and the Classification of the Topics Belonging to its Several Provinces", 1887 (Reel 36)
    - F.B. Sanborn, address, 1887 (Reel 36)
    - TD, "Property", 1887 (Reel 36)
    - "Property in Land": letters from Lyman Abbott and H.L. Wayland, 1887 (Reel 36)
    - WTH, "Right of Property and the Ownership of Land", 1887 (Reel 36)
    - "The Single Tax Debate": addresses by TD, WTH, Samuel B. Clarke, William Lloyd Garrison, J.B. Clark, E. Benjamin Andrews, Edwin R.A. Seligman, Louis F. Post, Edward Atkinson, Henry George, and James R. Carret, 1890 (Reel 36)
    - F.B. Sanborn, "Circular of the American Social Science Association", 1890 (Reel 36)
    - WTH, "Department of Education", 1883 (Reel 36)
    - WTH, "Moral Education in the Common Schools", 1884 (Reel 36)
    - WTH, "On the Function of the Study of Latin and Greek in Education", 1885 (Reel 36)
    - WTH, "Social Science and Social Conditions", 1886 (Reel 36)
    - TD, "The Place of Art in Education", 1886 (Reel 36)
    - William Ordway Partridge, "The Relation of the Drama to Education", 1886 (Reel 36)
  - Westminster Review: "TD, "American Education" (film 10), 1887 (Reel 36)
  - G.H. Howison, "St. Louis Reminiscences" (typescript) (film 11), 1916 (Reel 36)
  - St. Louis Public Schools. Board of Directors. Annual Reports (film 12), 1868-1875, 1880 (Reel 36)
    WTH (superintendent), various reports from vols. 14-20, 25, expressing his educational philosophy.
  - Charles Bradley Lindsley, "The Educational Philosophy of Thomas Davidson" (Ph.D. thesis, University of Cincinnati) (film 13), 1926 (Reel 36)
  - Antonio Stoppani, "Antonio Rosmini e la Fortnightly Review ," Rassegna Nazionale (film 14), 1885 (Reel 36)
  - P.K. O'Leary, "The Educational Work and Thought of Antonio Roshini Serbati (1787-1855): with Special Reference to his Minor Works" (M.A. thesis, Queen's University of Belfast) (film 15) (film 14), 1959 (Reel 37)